Monitoring and controlling the project
work.
So if you're following along in your
pinbox, that's page 105, 105.
Oh, so important.
All right.
So fail to plan?
Plan to fail.
We need to plan.
Have our scope, our schedule, our costs
agreed upon.
Know where we're going, what it is we're
setting out to a accomplish.
All right?
Well, what's the use
of having a plan if we
don't review, track,
monitor progress against it?
So huge here is where we will compare our
plan, what was agreed upon, our baselines,
the schedule, the scope.
Always start with the scope.
Scope has to be agreed upon first.
Based on the scope, we can
determine how long it's going to
take, the schedule baseline,
and create our cost baseline.
What's going to cost us, resources,
but we will have our baselines.
We will compare what was agreed upon that
was in our plan, our baselines,
to the data.
What's actually happening again, we're
trying to see if there is any variance.
We're trying to catch any problems as
quickly as possible.
So we can implement a change request.
All right.
So I know I'm snapping my fingers.
but oh so important you have a plan for a
reason this is what was agreed upon we
compare our plan to what is actually
happening again that's called work
performance data so we can quickly take
action if we find variance so that's the
key here we're looking for variance all
right so let's look at the second slide
we're tracking the progress of the
project's performance we'll compare actual
performance, that work performance data,
to the plan.
Remember, your plan includes your
baselines.
We'll determine if there is any variance.
Are we off of the scope, the schedule,
the cost, the quality?
So we can quickly take action.
That will require a change request.
All right, once we're baseline, once we
have our baselines agreed upon, we will.
We will, We'll need a change request,
okay?
All right, so with the change request,
we will take corrective action.
So we can get back in alignment with our
plan or take preventive action.
Something happened earlier.
Now we're going to take steps
through a change request to make
sure from here on out, we
stay in alignment with our plan.
We don't get off track or defect repair.
So often we'll see.
this one we're controlling quality we will
compare we will we our team will inspect
our deliverables be checking the
deliverables to make sure they are correct
complete they conform meet the
requirements and expectations they meet
compliance if not we will have a change
request for defect repair that deliverable
now usually tangible a defect is typically
tangible but I have heard of a process,
heard of a process being defective.
Usually tangible.
So something has to be fixed.
So if we're creating these pins,
for example, that's supposed to have this
little, you know, thing to get the pointer
in and out, whatever, supposed to have
this little thing so you can put it on
your shirt, whatever the case is.
all right any piece at this pin does not
meet the requirements or expectations or
comply that is called a defect that has to
be corrected so that's why it's typically
tangible a tangible defect we have
something that does not conform all right
we'll also ensure approved change requests
are implemented and checked so if we put
in a change request for defect repair we
have to make sure this was actually
corrected the defect was fixed all right
all right so over on the next slide we're
comparing some kind of reiterating what we
talked about we're comparing our plan what
was agreed upon to work performance data
what is actually happening and yep that's
during executing as we're doing the work
of the project I'm doing this again and
referring back to our process map and
executing process group.
All right.
So in Monitor and Control the project work
where we, the PM, oversee everything,
we will look at all the work performance
information that will come out of every
monitoring and controlling process below
us.
So if you look at the process map again,
page 25 in your PIMBOC, we are in
integration overseeing everything that's
happening with the project.
We manage, coordinate, unify that entire
project.
So everything happening below,
all the progress, information that's
coming out of each of the knowledge areas,
the scope, the schedule, the cost,
the quality, etc.
All rolls up to us.
All that work performance information
rolls up to us.
That's the progress.
We will put all that information together
to create those work performance reports
that we just talked about and we're going
to talk about again.
All right.
So we, the whole reason
for monitoring and controlling,
we're looking for variants
so we can quickly take action.
That will be through a change request
because we're already baselined.
And we will do this throughout our
project.